<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on From Mind to Quill</title>
    <link>http://prashantaher.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on From Mind to Quill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>aherPrashant70@gmail.com (Prashant Aher)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>aherPrashant70@gmail.com (Prashant Aher)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 16:00:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://prashantaher.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular: Getting started (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://prashantaher.com/post/angular-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 16:00:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aherPrashant70@gmail.com (Prashant Aher)</author>
      <guid>http://prashantaher.com/post/angular-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-angular-js&#34;&gt;What is Angular JS?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Angular JS &lt;a href=&#34;&#34; target=_blank&gt;official website &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AngularJS is a structural framework for dynamic web apps. It lets you use HTML as your template language and lets you extend HTML&amp;rsquo;s syntax to express your application&amp;rsquo;s components clearly and succinctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angular&amp;rsquo;s data binding and dependency injection eliminate much of the code you would otherwise have to write. And it all happens within the browser, making it an ideal partner with any server technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angular JS is a Javascript framework for writing HTML based web applications. It&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;code&gt;MVC&lt;/code&gt; framework where you have HTML templates as views, Javascript controllers to manage those views, and services for code reuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-angular-js&#34;&gt;Why Angular JS?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some reasons why you should consider using Angular JS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-dom-manipulations-where-they-belong&#34;&gt;1. DOM manipulations where they belong&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angular sees the view as just another HTML page with placeholders for data. So you do not mix your HTML rendering logic with your business logic. Because of it&amp;rsquo;s two way binding, controllers and views are tightly coupled. Just bind a placeholder to a variable and Angular will take care of rendering it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;2-dependency-injection&#34;&gt;2. Dependency injection&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dependency Injection (DI) is a software design pattern that deals with how components get hold of their dependencies.
The Angular injector subsystem is in charge of creating components, resolving their dependencies, and providing them to other components as requested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;3-two-way-data-binding&#34;&gt;3. Two way data binding&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angular has two way data binding, where a model variable is bound to a HTML element that can both change and display the value of the variable. You can have more than one HTML element bound to the same variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;4-directive&#34;&gt;4. Directive&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directives are nothing but html tags on steroids. With directives you never have to manipulate DOM again. While using a widget (for example accordian, carousel), imagine if you could just write single HTML tag and a bind a variable to it. No DOM manipulations, no user event handling (for example closing, hiding). I know that would be just amazing. With directives you can do all those stuff.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;You can define your own directives too!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;5-other-features&#34;&gt;5. Other features&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routing (Write single page web applications)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scope inheritance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean, modular, reusable architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These reasons should give you an idea of why Angular is powerful. In the next part we will implement a small Geocoding application with Angular JS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a static website</title>
      <link>http://prashantaher.com/post/static-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 03:33:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aherPrashant70@gmail.com (Prashant Aher)</author>
      <guid>http://prashantaher.com/post/static-sites/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-github-pages&#34;&gt;Why GitHub pages?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking of writing a blog or a portfolio? Want a personal website with your own domain? Don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with troubles of hosting the website yourselfs?&lt;br /&gt;
If your answer is yes to the above questions, then &lt;a target=_blank href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; is what you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-you-need-to-know&#34;&gt;What you need to know?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a website with GitHub Pages, you should know how to write &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&#34;&gt;Markdowns&lt;/a&gt;. No need of reading the Wikipedia link.&lt;br /&gt;
If you are new to markdowns, take this quick &lt;a target=_blank href=&#34;http://www.markdowntutorial.com&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;hugo&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdowns are the only thing you should know to get started with GitHub pages, but we want more than just ugly looking webpages. We want themes, discussion plugins. We can use Jekyll for the same as suggested on GitHub pages website. Personally I felt Jekyll was not easy to begin with. So I looked around and found &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=_blank&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo can be made up and running in minutes. Just some commands and steps to follow. People have developed few themes which you can directly use on your website.&lt;br /&gt;
You can find those themes &lt;a target=_blank href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and Hugo getting started &lt;a target=_blank href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/introduction/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is created using &lt;a target=_blank href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/beautifulhugo/&#34;&gt;this theme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://prashantaher.com/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:40:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aherPrashant70@gmail.com (Prashant Aher)</author>
      <guid>http://prashantaher.com/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A thought popped out of nowhere , why don&amp;rsquo;t I write a blog!! Response came &lt;em&gt;Go ahead&lt;/em&gt;. Then the next question was &amp;lsquo;What I should write?&amp;rsquo;.
I still don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer for the same. Starting with &lt;code&gt;Hello World!&lt;/code&gt; while learning &lt;strong&gt;Github Pages&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Hugo&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>